Kurt Duran Yalcin

Design Researcher & Manager | www.kurtyalcin.com | Santa Barbara, CA

I am a senior designer with a passion for research. I have 10 years experience working in an array of industries including publishing and FinTech. I'm comfortable managing design teams and working cross-functionally to drive internal alignment around a shared design vision.

Experience

FutureFuel.io | Series A start-up (25-50 employees)

Head of Design & Research | Aug 2020 — Present Senior User Experience Researcher | Mar 2019 — Aug 2020

- Grow and manage product design team of 4
- Mantain Storybook design system with engineering team
- Lead generative and evaluative research efforts
- Blend qual & quant data for product improvement
- Run A/B tests with Google Optimize and HotJar
- Reduced onboarding by 11 minutes post beta test

DesignLab & IDF | EdTech platform

Design Mentor | Jan 2019 — Present

Advise students in 1-on-1 sessions as mentor & instructor

Advance Local | Large national media group (350 employees)

Head of Design & Research | Sept 2018 — Mar 2019 Senior User Experience Researcher | Jan 2017 — Sept 2018

- Managed and hired for user experience design team of 3
- Increased perceived organization of site by 32% with testing
- Conducted a diary study with 5 readers during Senate election
- Designed interface that increased CTR to photo galleries 1%
- Run A/B tests with Google Optimize and HotJar
- Created 30+ surveys and analyzed 5400+ open text responses

Hearst Newspapers | Leading media company (3000 employees)

User Experience Architect | Nov 2014 — Dec 2016

- Moderated 1:1 usability testing in Albany, Houston, and SF
- Analyzed 35+ hours of recordings from prototype test
- Rearchitected reader's profile management system & SSO
- Sketched, wireframed, and designed prototypes

betaworks (Poncho), Alice App | Multiple start-ups and incubators Freelance User Experience Designer | Aug 2014 — Nov 2014

Skillshare | EdTech platform

Marketing Strategist | Sept 2013 — Feb 2014

UGallery | Online art gallery

Marketing & Community Manager | Mar 2012 — Jun 2013

Bloomspot | Daily deals website

Copywriter & Designer | Jun 2011 — Dec 2011

Education

Pratt Institute M.S. Information Experience Design GPA 3.975 | Aug 2016 – May 2018

General Assembly User Experience Design Certificate Apr 2014 — Aug 2014

New York University Dual B.A. Journalism & Urban Design GPA 3.583 | Sept 2007 – May 2011

Tools

Amplitude Iira Confluence Miro Hotlar Mixpanel **UserTesting Figma User Interviews** Sketch Google Optimize Plant Plugin **Google Analytics** Invision Adobe Illustrator MailChimp Adobe Photoshop PlaybookUX **Powerpoint**

Writing

"Not Just a Pretty Picture Part Two: Testing A Visual Literacy Program for Young Children)," Journal of Documentation medium.com/@kurtsy kurtsy.substack.com

Social

linkedin.com/in/kurtsy github.com/kurtsy instagram/@kurtsy twitter/@kurtduranyalcin

Contact

kyalcin@gmail.com 443.610.5268 References available upon request